emilycblack95@gmail.com emilyblack95.github.io

Summary

Computer Science professional with two years of programming experience. Dedicated, self-motivated and hardworking, I tackle any challenge that crosses my path and take the extra steps to ensure my code works efficiently and is well documented. I'm also known for thinking outside the box when it comes to innovative ideas.

Skills & Abilities

Java, C++, Python, SQL, Git, JavaScript, NoSQL, Node.js, C, HTML, CSS, Cloud, Microservices

Experience

Teacher Assistant, University of Oklahoma

05/2018 - 08/2018

- Facilitated a professor in helping run an Introduction to Programming class, with about ~200 students.
- Aided students in both weekly labs and office hours.
- Graded both the projects and online coding questions, as well as helping proctor the exams.

Software Development Intern, IBM

05/2018 - 08/2018

- Interned in the IBM CIO's office in the Identity and Access Management domain, developing tooling and automation to aid in self-service registration for SSO.
- Refined a micro services replacement to a monolithic application that enables applications owners to self-register applications supporting OIDC and SAML.

Virtualization Engineer Intern, Verizon

06/2017 - 08/2017

- Worked with an internal virtual acceleration team to create and manage Windows and Red Hat Linux servers on virtual machines for clients, using a platform called vSphere.
- Completed a certified two-day course called "VMware vSphere: Skills for Operators" that gave hands on experience.
- Placed 1st in Verizon's company-wide intern hackathon, and our solution is currently being considered for a patent.

Research Assistant, University of Oklahoma

08/2016 - 12/2016

- Worked on an application called Transit Assistant that assists ODOT agencies around the state to perform taxi services.
- Enhanced the backend by modifying C# classes and fixing bugs for the desktop application.
- Rewrote XAML & C# files to follow the MVVM standard.

Software Engineer Intern, Verizon 06/2016 – 08/2016

- Renovated an internal enterprise framework tool that generates HTML based on JSON objects or REST end points.
- Improved existing code by adding more efficient functionality and patching bugs.
- Slashed ~82% of development time with this application, which yielded roughly \$1.6M in cost savings.

Information Technology Concierge, University of Oklahoma 08/2015 – 12/2015

- Performed under a team called 'Boomer Buzz', which assisted students in the Bizzell Library with any technology needs.
- Advocated all technology related activities in the Bizzell Library.

Education

University of Oklahoma – Computer Science (GPA: 3.2)

Activities and Societies: ACM, Association for Women in Computing, Jerry Holmes Leadership Program, Software Studio, OU E-Sports Association.

Awards: Dean's Honor Roll, Josh Lee Speech Competition, One U Cup, School of Comp. Sci. T-Shirt Contest